# **Dennis Bereznyak**

bereznd1@tcnj.edu | 267-391-5741 | Holland, PA <u>Portfolio</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u>

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative, passionate developer who has been working in the Web field for 3 years, with prior experience learning Web-related skills while studying Interactive Multimedia in college. Experienced in technologies such as **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **jQuery**, **Firebase**, **APIs**, **MySQL**, **NodeJS**, & **ExpressJS**.. Driven to create solutions for tech issues while also focusing on practical details to ensure that these ideas come to fruition.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, APIs, AJAX, Firebase, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, HandlebarsJS, Sequelize, MochaJS & Chai Unit Testing, MVC Design Pattern, Bootstrap, Responsive Design, MomentJS, VelocityJS, Mapbox API, AngularJS, Information Architecture, Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Wordpress, UI/UX Design, Material Design, Balsamiq, Final Cut Pro

### **EDUCATION**

## University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania

1/2018 - 7/2018

Penn LPS Coding BootCamp - Javascript Full Stack Web Development
An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned include HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, HandelbarsJS & ReactJS.

# The College of New Jersey, Ewing, New Jersey

5/2017

*B.A. - Interactive Multimedia/Minor - Communication Studies* | 3.7 GPA | Cum Laude Thirteen-course Bachelor of Arts degree that combines hands-on instruction using industry-standard tools with in-depth exploration of the cultural impact of digital and interactive technology.

Relevant Coursework: Design Fundamentals for the Web, Mobile Computing, Dynamic Web
Applications, Intro to Interactive Computing, Interactive Design for Developing Communities,
Business Information Systems & Technology

### **PROJECTS**

Eat-Da-Burger Full Stack App | NodeJS, ExpressJS, MySQL, HandlebarsJS, jQuery | Github | Live

- Allows users to interact with a database, which then affects the information presented to them in their browsers.
- Lead developer.
- Used ExpressJS to set up a server that listens for AJAX requests based on a user's actions, which affects items within a MySQL database.

**Tune Tracker** | Firebase, APIs/AJAX, jQuery, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap | Github | Live

- Displays work of local musicians on a map to facilitate collaboration amongst local artists.
- Lead developer of API & Firebase-related features.
- Integrated Firebase with Mapbox API to store user input from a form and display it on the map based on users' geographic locations.

Movie Gif Retrieval | ¡Query, APIs/AJAX, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap | Github | Live

- Allows users to retrieve a set of playable gifs based on a movie of their choice.
- Lead developer.

# **Dennis Bereznyak**

# Page 2 of 2

• Developed jQuery app that sends AJAX requests to the GIPHY & OMDB APIs in order to display movie information.

### LIRI Command Line Node App | NodeJS, APIs/AJAX, JavaScript | Github

- Takes in users' commands and retrieves data based on what they entered.
- Lead developer.
- Programmed Node app to interpret user commands, send AJAX requests to the Twitter, Spotify, & ODMB API's, and then display desired data within terminal window.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection | Trenton, NJ

3/2015 - Present

Web Designer

- Improved the design & functionality of the organization's web presence by restructuring various department websites using *HTML*, *CSS*, *jQuery*, *JavaScript*, *Dreamweaver*, & *Photoshop*.
- Implemented improvements to the overall *UI/UX Design* & *Information Architecture* of department websites, allowing the organization to communicate its message online more effectively.
- Managed 5 websites regularly to ensure that they remained up-to-date and free of any technical issues, providing visitors with an efficient interface to retrieve their desired information.

# The College of New Jersey | Ewing, NJ

4/2014 - 3/2016

HR Web Assistant

- Implemented improvements to department's **Wordpress** website, which allowed information to be presented more effectively for user consumption.
- Managed web content in a timely manner, which ensured that visitors always received the most up-to-date and relevant information.